## Łukasz Cieśluk

### Personal details

Residence: Dublin, Ireland

GitHub: https://github.com/garciapl Blog: https://garciapl.github.io

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/lukaszciesluk

### **Summary**

Professional Software Engineer with over six years of extensive experience within financial, telco, advertising and commerce industries. Highly self-motivated individual contributor and team player focused on clean code approach combined with high quality. An advocate of automation in projects and enthusiast of open source.

## Experience

II.202I - now

Software Developer, Bloomberg LP Dublin, Ireland

Bloomberg AIM (Asset and Investment Manager)

Stack: Python

12.2017 - now

Senior Software Developer, Bloomberg Data Management Services Dublin, Ireland

 $\label{lem:enhancement} Enhancement\ of\ Enterprise\ Data\ Management\ with\ Market\ Index\ Data\ functionality\ in\ microservice\ environment$ 

Stack: Java, Python, Spring (Boot, Data, MVC), Maven, Flyway, Oracle, Guava, JUnit, Mockito, AssertJ, RabbitMQ, Kafka, Git, Ansible, Swagger, Elasticsearch, JavaScript, ExtJS

#### 4.2017 - II.2017

# Senior Software Developer, Datalex Limited Dublin, Ireland

- I. Develop application for storing and managing flights and other additional services
- 2. Bring code style within clean code approach and new practices in terms of development and testing
- 3. Compose performance scripts in JMeter
- 4. Perform code reviews along with mentoring other developers

Stack: Java, Gradle, RESTEasy, MongoDB, Morphia, JUnit, Mockito, Hamcrest, JMeter

#### 8.2015 - 3.2017

## Software Developer, Brandtone Dublin, Ireland

- I. Develop primary campaign management system that engages consumers through different channels like IVR, SMS and USSD. First developer of Konnect engagement platform which empowers marketers to maximize ROI and build deep relationships with consumers. Involved in developing Trader solution which helps traders improve selling their products
- 2. Cooperation with QA's, DevOps, DBA's, Architects and other Developers to build software which meets business requirements and KPIs
- 3. Participate in Agile Sprint planning, backlog refinement and retrospectives
- 4. Experience of working in environment which requires excellent troubleshooting, analytical skills, ability to be self-organised, strong interpersonal, communication skills and experience with a number of stack components and tools
- 5. Perform code reviews and documentation enhancement

Stack: Java, Spring (MVC, Data, Security, Batch, Integration), Maven, Oracle, Guava, Git, JUnit, Mockito, Grunt, Bower, Flyway, Docker, Ansible, ActiveMQ, AWS, Angular, React, Redux

#### 8.2014 - 6.2015

### Senior Java Developer, Digital Virgo Warsaw, Poland

- I. Develop mobile Value Added Services e.g. massive SMS sending service. Design dedicated standalone client for lottery system. Support developers involved in mobiParking project. Implement SMS Payment Gateways responsible for charging clients for content and services
- 2. Collaboration with business analysts around fulfilling client requirements
- 3. Partnership with developers responsible for the frontend
- 4. Preparation of technical and user documentation

Stack: Java, Spring (MVC, Data), Maven, Oracle, Git, Swing, Python

#### II.20I3 - 7.20I4

# Software Developer, AgreeYa Mobility Poland Warsaw, Poland

- Develop supply system dedicated to the medical industry in accordance with customer requirements
- 2. Direct collaboration with the client in order to select technologies and solutions applied
- 3. Composition of technical and user documentation of produced software

Stack: Java, Python, Django, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL

#### 7.2012 - 10.2013

## Software Developer, Bank Gospodarstwa Krajowego Warsaw, Poland

- I. Leading role in incorporate new extensions of system responsible for monitoring bank infrastructure e.g. execution of money transfers, network stability, databases availability and other banking systems
- 2. Support supervisor during the design and implementation of new data models and graphs commissioned by Bank management and other departments
- 3. Overall system administration and maintenance

Stack: Java, Perl, Oracle, MySQL, Cisco, Nagios

The intern was founded in XVII edition of the competition "Grasz o Staż" organized by PwC

#### 7.20II - 9.20II

## Software Developer (intern), Telekomunikacja Polska Warsaw, Poland

Implement tool improving the efficiency of administrator work around collecting and analysing Call Detail Records (CDR) used for billing customers for paid services

Stack: Java, Perl, PostgreSQL

The intern was founded in XVI edition of the competition "Grasz o Staż" organized by PwC

#### 7.2010 - 9.2010

## Software Developer (intern), Orange Poland Warsaw, Poland

Support administrators in the current surveillance and response to the failure of IT systems responsible for the proper operation of the GSM/UMTS mobile networks. Develop tools to improve and enhance operational efficiency

Stack: Perl, Bash

The intern was founded in XV edition of the competition "Grasz o Staż" organized by PwC

## **Education**

2.2011 - 10.2012

Politechnika Bialostocka (Bialystok, Poland)

**Faculty: Computer Studies** 

Specialization: Smart Internet Technologies

Degree: MSc

Thesis: Analysis tools used to implement the concept of Telco 2.0

The master thesis was carried out in collaboration with <u>Orange Poland</u> under initiative Orange Labs Telco 2.0 University

As the part of the thesis was developed application called Eventoo which aims to monitor the correlation between the area defined by event organizer for instance as a festival and the location of participants based on the operator localization interface to provide statistics and tools to collaborate with them

Framework - Spring (Core, Data, Web)

Database - MongoDB

UI - JSP, jQuery

APIs - Orange Location and SMS API, Facebook API

I0.20II - 2.20I2

Politechnika Lodzka (Lodz, Poland)

Faculty: Technical Physics, Computer Science and Applied Mathematics Specialization: Systems in management and electronic commerce

Degree: MSc

The semester has been completed as part of a student exchange program called MOSTECH dedicated to students of technical universities

I0.2007 - 2.20II

Politechnika Bialostocka (Bialystok, Poland)

**Faculty: Computer Studies** 

Specialization: Designing Application Systems

Degree: BSc

Thesis: Secure communication using SMS

Platform - Java ME

Cryptographic algorithms - DES, AES

## **Scholarships**

2011 - 2012 University President Scholarship at Politechnika Bialostocka

2010 - 2011 Scholarship at Politechnika Bialostocka

### Certifications

2.2018 Bloomberg Market Concepts (BMC)

5.2016 ScrumMaster by Scrum Alliance (License no. 000527091)

II.2015 | Java SE 7 Programmer | (IZ0-803)

## Languages

Polish: native

English: upper-intermediate

#### Additional

Winner of 15, 16 and 17 edition of competition "Grasz o Staż" https://www.facebook.com/graszostaz

Languages | Java, Python

Frameworks | Spring (Boot, Data, MVC, Cache, Batch, Integration)

Databases | Oracle (PL/SQL), MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis

NoSQL | MongoDB

Web Servlets, JSP, JSON, HTML, REST XML XPath, XQuery, XSLT, JAXB

Application server | Apache Tomcat

Persistence Hibernate, JPA, JDBC, PL/SQL Message Broker RabbitMQ, ActiveMQ, Apache Kafka

Testing | JUnit, Mockito, Hamcrest, DbUnit, WireMock, AssertJ

ELK Elasticsearch, Kibana

Version Control | Git, Subversion

Libraries | Guava, Apache Commons, JodaTime, Lombok

IDE IntelliJ, Eclipse

Operating Systems | Linux, Windows Build automation | Maven, Bower, Gulp

Database Migration | Flyway | Cloud | AWS\*

DevOps Docker, Ansible SDLC Scrum (Agile)

Collaboration | JIRA, BitBucket, Confluence | Jenkins, Nexus, SonarQube

Principles | SOLID

<sup>\* -</sup> in progress